Abderrahman Lahiaouni

SUMMARY

"Research and development engineer, graduated from an engineering school, experience extends from IT consulting to research, relevant technical skills as well as communication skills working in positions involving marketing and public relations as well as traveling. Fast learner, excited to see new things, with a strong sense of commitment, fellowship and cheerfulness"

WORK EXPERIENCE

MAR 2020 - JAN 2023 (FT)

Consistee engineering and consulting gmbh – Saarbruecken *Senior software engineer*

Worked on transforming a legacy infrastructure to enable fast development, testing and deployment through tools such as Ansible and Docker. In addition to working on developing and maintaining a monitoring CLI python tool for customer servers running our product, and making up-to-date documentation for existing rest-apis using OpenAPI.

DEC 2018 - DEC 2019 (FT)

Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique (INRIA) – Lille

Research and development engineer - Spirals

The project aims to make formal verification of large complex software systems described with formal specification languages doable on a larger scale, by leveraging Grid5000 research infrastructure, making big SAT problems that are slow to solve locally, deployable remotely, with convenient result retrieval and reporting.

Project tasks involved making: Restful api specs. A containerized server in Go that will do the reservation, configuration and deployment of clusters automatically using Docker Machine, Ansible and Kubernetes, Assemble the server with Nginx reverse proxy, and an internal VPN using Docker Compose. A fork client Alloy Analyzer open-source tool.

 $MAI\ 2018 - NOV\ 2018$ (FT)

INRIA - Lille

Intern for Graduation Project - Spirals

As part of the spirals team, –particularly interested in introducing more automation in the adaptation mechanisms of software systems– I worked on a project focused on cloud storage, more specifically on load balancing and data replication aspects. The emphasis was on practical outcomes concerning data popularity, network traffic and available resources

 $JUL\ 2017-SEP\ 2017\ \ (FT)$

Algo Consulting group **Summer internship**

First experience in a professional environment. I worked on a customer survey mobile application. I was given 3 days to acquire basics of .NET, Xamarin.Forms and make a first prototype of the app, which I did and became part of the production team.

Tasks involved writing logic and UI using C# and XAML (Mystery Shopper)

single, 29yo

Türkismühler str 19 66113 Saarbrücken Deutschland

+49 17 63 44 18 202

lahiaouni.abd@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/lahiaouni-

abderrahman/

in https://github.com/AbderrahmanL

EDUCATION

2013 – 2018 Engineer degree

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

National School of Applied Sciences

2012 baccalaureate

Department of Math

Rahaly El Farouq High school

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FULL-STACK Spring boot, Vue.js, bootstrap

DEVOPS Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible

maven, jenkins, gradle

git, github, gitlab-ci, Azure Devops

Languages Java, Sql, c/c++

Python, c#

html5, css, PHP, JavaScript

os Debian, CentOS, Arch

Windows, OS X

DB PostgreSQL, Oracle, Mysql

CERTIFICATIONS Test driven development using

python, pytest, and mock

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

TALKS More Intelligent Web 3.0

Microservices and OOP principles

workshops .Net intro

The Blockchain

LANGUAGES Arabic

French English

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Goal Oriented

I believe in action over long-winded discussions, listen to everyone's viewpoints then draw a judgment based on reached consensus to immediately act and achieve goals quickly and efficiently.

Passionate

I have been interested in computer sciences from an early age. Academic and professional experiences have cemented this interest into a passion. I greatly enjoy carrying out fundamental and technical aspects in IT with practical and useful applications.